hi everybody today we are gonna make
super simple
Oreo gelato
this is going to be a cold process one
so no heating at all so if you want to
see how we get on let's go and do this
like I said really easy cold process
gelato today and the bowl still wet
what does that mean cold process well it
means we're not going to heat this at
all we are going to put all our
ingredients into a bowl and a whisk it
and combine it cold the xanthan gum
we're going to use in here for the
stabilizer that doesn't need heating
either and then we can actually just
Churn it nice and quick so
what do we need we need a bowl
we have our milk powder
sugar and our dextrose and our xanthan
gum
I don't have my little scales they were
in the fire so I'm going to take a punt
really for this I need about two and a
half grams
you say it's about that much
put that in
[Applause]
that in get some little scales
you can't use
little tiny spoons to measure stabilizer
there we go all in there you're going to
stir this
just combining your stabilizer with your
sugars
and what that does is it stops any
clumping of your stabilizer and make
sure that it incorporates into your base
completely
there we go
just like that all right let's get our
milk and our cream out fridge
I'll move the camera down a bit
there we go you can see the bowl now
whipping cream
two percent milk
right
how much do I need
so 600 grams
of
milk
grams
might just go in here
grams of milk
into our Bowl
and
150 of cream
in
done
set
it's all the weighing Parts done
obviously I did the milk powder and the
such before but
first thing is our milk powder I'm just
going to put that in get a whisk
and
this is good milk powder it dissolves
really really easily
so
if you're cold processing ice cream just
have to do a fair bit of stirring okay
so there we go
in with that and then in with
our sugars and our stabilizer mix
and now we're just going to stir this
for
five or six minutes
stuff everywhere and make sure it's all
completely dissolved okay I'm just going
to test that take a nice deep spoon put
it down in the bottom spoon it out and
you'll see granules if you're unsure
nope
no graininess no bit no bits of this
that and the other nice and smooth so
we're gonna prepare our Oreos we can put
this in the fridge while we do that
Oreos
take a bag
[Applause]
take some areas we actually only want
the outside
first so we're gonna separate those
put them in the bag nice
nice
I'll speed through this bit
okay
we got lots of these
we're gonna do sandwich them back
together so
it's kind of like
cookies and cream gelato
Oreo gelato cookies and cream gelato
call it what you like
so we're going to take those smush them
back together
and they will go in it's kind of like
double stuff now
and now go back in
during the journey
here we go double stuffed Oreos put
those aside one for me
then we're going to crush these in the
bag
get the air out of the bag
crushes up good
with
nothing
this is all I have
[Music]
Oreo powder
everything's ready
let's get the ice cream out the fridge
[Music]
machine okay it's been in there like
five minutes you know just just enough
time to process those you can see the
xanthan gum was already doing its thing
there's no bits in there at all we've
tested it make sure all the sugars
dissolved all the milk powders dissolved
that's kind of it we're not gonna put
any vanilla in here at all
right
machines pre-chilled
let's get churning
[Music]
okay it's starting to come together
we're gonna put in our Oreo powder now
we'll leave that finish off for another
five six minutes
this is one of the only times where you
have to wait
for the ice cream really if you're
making it yourself
gelato is served between 10 and 12
degrees under so minus 10 minus 12. and
most freezers are just much colder than
that
if you've got a freezer and you only
make gelato and you can adjust it to
that temperature great then you'll never
have an issue going and scooping as long
as it's a stabilized ice cream you'll be
fine
but my freezer is also full of other
stuff
let's get some scooped up out of our
cupcake tub
into this little bowl and see what this
tastes like
[Music]
thank you
skipped nice nice a lot of cookie stuff
in there when you use the powder
you know the actual Oreo cookie itself
when you absolutely decimate it into
powder and you put it in your ice cream
your ice cream goes as kind of like gray
brown color
um it's not particularly attractive but
once you or as you know what this is
this is just Oreos
you kind of Let It Go
there's no other flavoring it's just
Oreo
see what it tastes like
that's good it's really good
it got me so close using xanthan gum in
gelato because gelato needs more
stabilizers than ice cream because of
the lower fat
xanthan gum isn't really the stabilizer
to use for gelato but
it's what I got at the moment so that's
what you use
but we got it right here it's got a
really nice texture loads of flavor that
Oreo comes through just if you had just
the ice cream without the other bits of
cookie and stuff in there
just tastes like pure cold
Oreo really nice
but you are also free to put in those
huge chunks of cookie as you saw I did
and that's um you know that's a real
bonus because most store-boughts don't
have a lot in there
that is good
nice and simple cold processed gelato
don't do cold process if you've got
other stabilizers
something come Go gum
they don't need heat to hydrate
so you're good to go
if you don't want to use stabilizers
then absolutely do this
I mean that's
probably the only thing holding you back
for cold precious ice cream anyway
you can do that with American ice cream
as well you don't need to heat every ice
cream recipe up it helps sometimes just
to dissolve certain ingredients but if
ingredients are good
you're good to go
leaves a really nice lasting Oreo taste
in your mouth this is a really nice one
anyway
this was requested by
a subscriber hope this is what you
wanted
I am gonna go on to likely Rolo ice
cream next week
is going to be two different ice creams
with Rolos and maybe even caramel sauce
I don't know I'm just going to go to
town
if you want to see what that turns out
like don't forget to like And subscribe
and I'll see you next week
[Music]